# ANKITH REDDY PATI

Boston | 617-352-5120 | ankithreddy137@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

#### **SUMMARY**

A Finance graduate embarking on a transformative journey into the world of Software Engineering. Committed to ongoing education and skill development. Drawing from my past experiences, I eagerly embrace challenging roles to apply my evolving skills, fostering a path of continuous improvement in this ever-evolving field.

#### **EDUCATION**

### NORTHEASTERN UNIVERSITY, Boston, MA, USA

**Expected Dec 2024** 

College of Engineering, Master of Science in Information Systems

Relevant Courses: Application Modeling & Design, Application Engineering & Development, Web Design & User Experience

Engineering, Data Structures & Algorithms, Networking & Cloud Computing, Agile Software Development

#### **SKILLS**

Programming Languages: Java, JavaScript, Python, PulumiDatabase Management Systems: MySQL, MongoDB, PostgresWeb Development: HTML, CSS/SCSS, React.js, Node.js.Tools: AWS, GCP, Git, Docker, Shell scripting

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Amazon Hyderabad, India

Apr. 2022-Aug. 2022

## **Transaction Risk Investigation Specialist**

- Utilized advanced data analysis techniques to investigate over 5000 transactions, identifying key patterns and anomalies. This process honed my analytical skills, crucial for debugging and optimizing software systems.
- Enhanced SOP's contributing to a 15 % increase in fraud detection efficiency and collaborated in enhancement of fraud detection tools, gaining experience in how software applications can be leveraged to improve business processes.

## Amazon, Hyderabad, India Machine learning Data Associate

Dec. 2018-Feb. 2021

- Engaged in a pivotal Nike pilot program, performing critical video and image tagging to capture interaction data for Amazon Robotics, bolstering the stowing efficiency of Amazon kiva robots in fulfillment center by 20%.
- Led detailed analytical sessions aimed at augmenting data-driven insights resulting in 10% improvement in data accuracy, thus substantially improving process efficiency and fostering potential advancements.
- Leveraging my expertise as a Subject Matter Expert, spearheaded training sessions on changes in SOP's, utilizing Kanban boards to facilitate seamless transitions and optimize workflow management for the team.

## DST Systems, Hyderabad, India Associate Investor Services

Dec. 2017-May. 2018

- Managed over 10,000 financial transactions for BlackRock as a third-party financial transaction processor, encompassing account openings, purchases, redemptions, asset transfers, systematic withdrawal plans and ACH transactions.
- Ensured 99.8% accuracy in transaction postings on the mainframe systems and audited high-value transactions, leading to 20% reduction in audit discrepancies among the team.
- Led a team of 15 associates to effectively handle Day 2 errors, delivering targeted training sessions that culminated in achieving a zero-defect rate.

### ACADEMIC PROJECT

- Developed a RESTful web application with NodeJS, MySQL and Sequelize (ORM), and established AWS infrastructure using Pulumi for automation.
  - o Created VPC, subnets, EC2 instances with load balancer and an autoscaling group which gets triggered by custom CloudWatch alarms. Implemented custom logs and metrics for webapp monitoring in CloudWatch.
  - o Setup robust CI/CD pipelines with GitHub Actions to perform Health checks, formatting checks, AMI creation, launch template updates, and ASG integration with newly created AMI's.
  - O Configured RDS, automated DNS management, and utilized an SNS Topic to trigger Lambda functions to perform GCP bucket uploads, email notification via mail gun, and email status updates in DynamoDB.
- Developed Nourish Bridge a food donation and distribution system, applying Object-Oriented programming principles for flexible and maintainable code.
  - O Implemented CRUD operations, robust class design and form validations for seamless data management.
  - O Designed Admin panel for efficient entity management, incorporated email notifications and maps.
  - O Streamlined stock management, donation requests, and volunteer coordination through a user-friendly registration system.

# **LEADERSHIP AND ACTIVITIES:**

- Secured first place and a 500 USD prize in Ethereum India 2021 hackathon, leveraging sponsor technology Alchemy for <u>CREDFI</u>.
- Attained CA foundation, and IT training certification from Institute of Chartered Accountants of India.
- Dedicated over a year as Crypto Relief volunteer, rigorously validating sources, addressing urgent aid requests and meticulously curating deployment data using Airtable for analytics and future audits.